## Thilagavathi S

Bangalore, India – (91) 8825980266 <u>thilagavathi68@gmail.com</u> – (https://www.linkedin.com/in/thilagavathi-selvaraj-b64230159)

#### **SUMMARY**

Trade Compliance Professional with expertise and knowledge in Harmonized Tariff Schedule (HTS Classification), Free Trade Agreements (FTA), Country of Origin(COO), Rules of Origin, ECCN, Restricted Party Screening, Generalized System of Preferences (GSP), International Trade, Incoterms, Trade barriers, Trade remedies, duty drawback and customs valuation. Experience in the following areas:

- HTS Classification
- FTA Solicitation (USMCA)
- FTA LTSD Declaration (EMEA)
- Team Management

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **KPMG** International Limited, Bangalore December 2022 – Present **Trade Compliance – Senior Associate** ☐ Create certificates, LTSD (Long Term Supplier Declaration) for EMEA region. ☐ Connect with clients regularly to understand their requirements and process documents related to certification on time. Perform BOM Analysis and identify the components of finished goods that are pending supplier declaration and qualify the finished goods. ☐ Audited the classified products (HTS Classification), Schedule B and CIQ by the associates. Also, follow up with concerned team to get all required details to perform classification when additional information is required. October 2021 – November 2022 **Ernst & Young LLP, Bangalore** <u>Trade Compliance – Senior Analyst</u> ☐ Manage a team of 3 members, connect with the team members to mentor and provide timely feedback regarding their KPA. ☐ Perform audit for the classified products (HTS Classification). Check for applicable trade remedies OGA and PGA. ☐ Perform document review on the FTA Solicitation (USMCA) documents and connect with

suppliers for required details and finalize the documents.

## **Trade Compliance - SME**

	Managed a team of 8 members where I mentored & provided technical support to the
	associates.
	As a SME, conducted training to the associates and also provide refresher training depending
	upon the requirement.
	Analysed the final duty rate of the product based on the country of origin to determine
	whether the product meets profitability requirements.
	POC for custom brokers where I resolve Importer Security Filing issues with respect to HTS
	Classification.
Flipk	art Internet Pvt Ltd, Bangalore November 2017 – December 2018
Quali	ty Assurance – Garment Fit Technician
	Responsible for private label Apparel & Clothing.
	Creating product specs and design packs for handover to factories within set deadlines.
	Updating and managing graded specs and sizing standards.
	Attend and lead fit sessions, prepare and relay fit comments to the factories and ensure these
	are accurately executed.
	Performed SWOT Analysis of Vendors regularly. Played a major role in RVP Reduction.
Page Industries Ltd (JOCKEY), Bangalore June 2014 – July 2015	
Quality Assurance - Officer	
	Developing SOP (Standard Operating Procedure) for quality checks at various levels of
	production for ensuring quality.
	Developing Tech-packs for the running styles.
	Coordinating with production department to resolve non- conformance issues.
	Oversee the auditing from cutting to packing section in Intimate Apparel Division.
	Conduct random inline, AQL & FI audits in the Intimate Apparel Division.
EDUCATION	
B.Tech in Textile Technology,	
Bannari Amman Institute of Technology, Tamil Nadu, India (CGPA 8.97)	

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Word), Edith and MIC Suite